# **Rachel Doogue**

45 Old Burrin, Burrin Road, Carlow Town, Carlow.

086 663 3038 / c00237335@itcarlow.ie / www.linkedin.com/in/rachel-doogue-softdev

Full Driving Licence

### **Personal Profile**

I am a highly motivated third year student Software Development student at the Institute of Technology Carlow. My first two years in college have helped me developed my communication, organisation, and problem-solving skills. As part of my course, I have worked on projects both as part of a team, recently using agile methodology, and as an individual. I would greatly appreciate an opportunity to take part in Google's Virtual Algorithms Workshop.

## **Technical Skills**

- Programming I have experience with Java, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, SQL and Assembly Language. This year I have been learning Python and C++.
- Office Tools Proficient in Microsoft Word, Excel, PowerPoint and Access.
- Programming Tools Last year I started using Eclipse IDE for Java Developers and Notepad++. This year I have been using Visual Studio IDE, Android Studio, and a Virtual Box to run a Linux operating system.
- Operating Systems In first year I studied both Windows and Linux. This year I have worked on a Linux operating system as part of one of my classes.

#### Education

Bachelor of Science (Honours) Software Development | Institute of Technology Carlow. September 2018 – present

# **Current Subjects**

- Advanced Programming
- Software Engineering for Web, Cloud and Mobile Apps
- Mobile Apps
- Discrete Structure and Algorithms II
- Web and Cloud Development
- Operating Systems

# **Relevant Work Experience**

- CoderDojo, Institute of Technology of Carlow | CoderDojo Volunteer
   October 2019 March 2020
  - o I helped the kids find and fix problems with their code.
  - Help them understand what the tutor was doing and why.

# **Other Work Experience**

- Vet & Pet, Carlow | Shop Assistant
   September 2015 November 2015
  - I spent most of my time in the main shop putting away new stock. I would keep the shelves organised and clean.
  - When I went out to farms with the vet, I recorded numbers on a device as he injected cows for tests.
  - o In the shop with the vet I would watch him perform surgery on dogs and cats.
- Sue Ryder's Charity Shop, Dublin Street, Carlow | Shop Assistant November 2015 – February 2016
  - Sorting donations to determine if they were fit for sale.
  - Putting price tags on these items.
  - Keeping the shop organised and clean.
- Intersport Elverys, Tullow Street, Carlow | Shop Assistant February 2016 – April 2016
  - Putting away new stock.
  - o I organised the back room where the shoes were kept and the shoe displays.
  - o Brushed and vacuumed the shop floor.

## **Interests**

Since starting college I have played with the IT Carlow Ladies Rugby Team. My position is on the wing. Before this I also played with my local rugby club, Carlow Rugby Club, first with the under 18's team and then moving up into the Carlow Coyotes Ladies Team. I played with the club from 2016 up until 2019. In 2018 I was awarded the coaches player of the year.

I enjoy going on long forest or mountain walks. In 2019 I climbed Carrauntoohil and Croagh Patrick over last summer. Since the Covid-19 lockdowns I have started walking around Carlow town, along the river Barrow and in Oak Park forest.

# References

Ms. Catherine Moloney Mr. Stuart Bryan IT Carlow Lecturer CoderDojo Tutor Catherine.Moloney@itcarlow.ie 087 918 4389